Thanh Tran

Junior Frontend Developer / IT Support



CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone

0421-468-291

Linkedin

linkedin.com/johnutw

Twitter

@johnsmithutw

E-Mail

j.smith@cvmaker.pro



EDUCATION

1996-09 -2001-05 Master of Computer Science, University of Maryland

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude.
- Member of Student Association of Project Management
- Managed a student project to develop a weekly IT News podcast.



SKILLS

Business Process Improvement- history of

successful innovations leading to cost savings.

- Vendor Management- proven track record of managing vendors in projects with budgets of over \$1'000'000.
- Project Scheduling- over 90% of projects led were finished in due time.
- Sales Analysis- background in IT Sales with deep understanding of negotiating contracts.



SUMMARY

IT Professional with over 10 years of experience specializing in IT department management for international logistics companies. I can implement effective IT strategies at local and global levels. My greatest strength is business awareness, which enables me to permanently streamline infrastructure and applications.



EXPERIENCE

2006-12 present

Senior Project Manager

Seton Hospital, ME

- Oversaw all major hospital IT projects for 10+ years, focus on cost reduction.
- Responsible for creating, improving, and developing IT project strategies.
- Implemented the highly successful Lean Training and Six Sigma projects for all employees.
- I reduced the costs of IT infrastructure maintenance by 5% in 2015 by successfully rebuilding the infrastructure.

2004-09 -2006-12

Junior Project Manager

.2 Seton Hospital, ME

- Streamlined IT logistics and administration operation cutting costs by 25%.
- Diagnosed problems with hardware and operating systems and implemented solutions to increase efficiency.
- Maintained the user database of over 30000 patients, implemented new solutions inside the dashboard.
- Managed project for lean training for all IT Support Officers.



CERTIFICATIONS

2015-05

PMP - Project Management Institute

2014-04

PRINCE2® Foundation